Guide to the Pacific Improvement Company Records, 1901-1966 JL017
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Land Department, 1917
  - “Corning, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 65)
  - “Crow's Landing, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 66)
  - “Delano, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 67)
  - “Dinuba, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 68)
  - “Dunsmuir, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 69)
  - “El Verano, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 70)
  - “Fowler, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 71)
  - “Fowler, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 72)
  - “Fresno, Calif. ”., Sept. - Dec. (Box 39, Folder 73)
  - “Fresno, Calif. ”., May - August (Box 39, Folder 74)
  - “Fresno, Calif. ”., Jan. - April (Box 39, Folder 75)
  - “Fruto, Glenn County, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 76)
  - “Galt, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 77)
  - “Gallatin Tract, Red Bluff, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 78)
  - “Goshen, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 79)
  - “Gridley, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 80)
  - “Hanford, Kings County, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 81)
  - “Herndon, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 82)
  - “Hickman, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 83)
  - “Huron, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 84)
  - “Kern County (Bakersfield), Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 85)
  - “Lemoore, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 86)
  - “Lethent, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 87)
  - “Los Banos, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 88)
  - “Lovelock, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 89)
  - “Maxwell, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 90)
  - “Mayhew Tract, Visalia, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 91)
  - “Mendota, Wash.”. (Box 39, Folder 92)
  - “Merced, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 93)
  - “Miniola, Ivesta, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 94)
  - “Modesto, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 95)
  - “Mojave, Kern County, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 96)
  - “Montague, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 97)
  - “Montpellier, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 98)
  - “Nelson, Calif.”. (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - “Newhall, Calif.”. (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - “Nord, Calif.”. (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - “Oakland, Calif.”. (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - “Crris, Calif.”. Porterville. (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - “Terrace, Elder County, Utah”. (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - “Reedley, Calif.” (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - “Reno, Washoe County, Nevada”. (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - “Rio Bravo, Calif.”. (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - “Ryer, Calif.”. (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - “Sanger, Calif.”. (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - “San Miguel, Calif.”. (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - “Santa Barbara, Calif.”. (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - “Santa Margarita, Calif.”. (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - “Santa Rose, Calif.”. (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - “Saticoy, Calif.”. (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - “Sheep Island, S.F., Calif.”. (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - “Sisson, Calif.”. (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - “Tipton, Tulare County, Calif.”. (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - “Tracy, Calif.”. (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - “Tulare, Tulare County, Calif.”. (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - “Tulare County Abstract Co. - Lubking”. Lubking is name of person who desires abstract of land. (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - “Truckee, Calif.”. (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - “Verdi, Washoe County, Nevada”. (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - “Wadsworthy, Nevada”. (Box 40, Folder 25)
  - “Waterford, Calif.”. (Box 40, Folder 26)
  - “Wells, Nevada”. (Box 40, Folder 27)
  - “Winnemucca, Nevada”. (Box 40, Folder 28)
  - “Placer County Calif. and Nevada Land”. (Box 40, Folder 29)
  - “Assessments and Taxes ”., Nov. - Dec. (Box 40, Folder 30)
  - “Assessments and Taxes Oct.”. (Box 40, Folder 31)
  - “Assessments and Taxes ”., Jan. - Sept. (Box 40, Folder 32)
  - “M.V. Gregg Tract - Payments”. Payments on principle of contracts. (Box 40, Folder 33)
  - “H.R. Verrue”. Notes accompanying and explaining remissions from collections. (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - “Oakland Water Front Co. ”., Jan. - Apr. (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - “Oakland Water Front Co. ”., May - Sept. (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - “Oakland Water Front Co. ”., Oct. - Dec. (Box 41, Folder 4)
- Land Department, 1920
  - “Alameda, Calif.”. (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - “Amsterdam, Calif.”. (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - “Battle Mountain, Lander County, Nevada”. (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - “Benson, Arizona”. (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - “Boulder Creek, Calif.”. (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - “Buttonwillow, Kern County, Calif.”. (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - “Caliente, Calif.”. (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - “Capay Valley, Calif.”. (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - “Coalinga, Calif.”. (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - “Colfax, Wash.”. (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - “Colton, Calif.”. (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - “Crow's Landing, Calif.”. (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - “Delano, Kern County, Calif.”. (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - “Deming, New Mexico”. (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - “Dinuba, Calif.”. (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - “El Verano, Calif.”. (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - “Exeter, Calif.”. (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - “Famosa, Calif.”. (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - “Fowler, Calif.”. (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - “Fresno, Calif. ”. Alta Vista Tract., Oct. - Dec. (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - “Fresno, Calif. ”. Alta Vista Tract., May - Sept. (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - “Fresno, Calif. ”. Alta Vista Tract., Jan. - April (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - “Galt, Calif.”. (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - “Gridley, Calif.”. (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - “Herndon, Calif.”. (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - “Hickman, Calif.”. (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - “Huron, Calif.”. (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - “Ingomar, Calif.”. (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - “Irrigosa, Madera County, Calif.”. (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - “Kern County (Bakersfield), Calif.”. (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - “Lathrop, Calif.”. (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - “Lemoore, Calif.”. (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - “Lethent, Calif.”. (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - “Lovelock, Nevada”. (Box 42, Folder 19)
  - “Mendota, Wash.”. (Box 42, Folder 20)
  - “Merced, Calif.”. (Box 42, Folder 21)
  - “Modesto, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - “Mojave, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - “Montague, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - “Newhall, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - “Newman, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - “Orland, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - “Palermo, Butte County, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - “Porterville, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - “Reedley, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - “Reno, Nevada”. (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - “Rio Bravo, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - “Rocklin, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - “Rolinda, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - “Ryer, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - “Sanger, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - “San Miguel, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - “Santa Barbara, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - “Santa Margarita, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - “Saticoy, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - “Smithson, Shasta County, Calif.”. Search by correspondence for two men, Joshua Harlan and Hiram Kellog, in order to straighten out deed to land that they sold to Underhill. (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - “Stanley, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - “Taurusa, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - “Traver, Tulare County, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - “Tulare, Tulare County, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - “Truckee, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - “Syndicate Lands, Calif.”. In Siskiyou, Colusa, Glenn, Tehama and Madera Counties. (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - “Waterford, Calif.”. (Box 43, Folder 27)
  - “Wells, Nevada”. (Box 43, Folder 28)
- Land Department (end), Crocker-Huffman Land & Water Co. General File (begin), 1920 1920 and 1921
  - “Winnemucca, Nevada”. (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - “Virginia Colony, Kern County, Calif.”. (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - “Lake Tahoe, Calif.”. (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - “Property Sales”. No particular location. (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - “Taxes”. No particular location. (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - “M.V. Gregg Tract, Sutter County, Calif.”. (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - “Oakland Water Front Co.”. (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - “Buffalo, N.Y. Properties”. (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - “J.H. Fullmer Option”. Extended by P.I. Co. to sell or buy lands (coal mines) in New Mexico. (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - “Crocker-Huffman L. & W. Co. Monthly Statistics 1920 and 1921”. Monthly reports compare financial figures to: 1. same month, previous years and 2. same year, previous months., (1917 - 1921) (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - “Crocker-Huffman Co. - Index to Correspondence ”. Files A-Z, recording all correspondence in C-H Co. general file., 1920 and 1921 (Box 44, Folder 11)
- Crocker-Huffman Land & Water Co. General File, 1920 & 1921
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Correspondence S.F.B. Morse and L.D. Van Horne, ”. Morse (in S.F.) sends memos authorizing Van Horne (in Merced) to do certain things and Van Horne notifies Morse of how certain projects are progressing., Dec. 1920 to March 1921 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Correspondence Accompanying Checks ”. C-H Co. checks had to be sent by E.M. Brown, the office manager, to Morse to be signed., 1921 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Correspondence Accompanying Checks 1920”. Contents similar to, 45-2. (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Miscellaneous ”. Correspondence from or about C-H Co. in Merced to Morse. Covering subjects from Christmas Turkeys for the Directors to the settling of a dead employee's estate., 1921 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - “C-H L. W. Co. - Miscellaneous 1920”. Contents similar to, 45-4. (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. Contributions to Charitable Organizations ”., 1920 and 1921 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Merced Irrigation District ”., 1921 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Merced Irrigation District ”., 1920 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Livestock and Meat Packing ”. Majority of the correspondence pertains to purchase of cattle., July - Dec. 1921 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. Livestock and Meat Packing ”. Contents similar to 45-9., Jan. 1920 - June 1921 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Personnel ”. Job applications and recommendations. Most of the hiring and firing goes on between Mors and Van Horne., 1920-1921 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Real Estate Trade ”. Correspondence and maps re: different possible trades where C-H Co. would receive an urban office bldg. for undeveloped Merced land., 1920 and 1921 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Legal Suits and Debts ”. Correspondence re: legal suits against C-H Co. and other bills and debts. Also some discussion of real estate deals., 1920 and 1921 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Dry Creek Reservoir ”. Reservoir site on C-H Co. land., Dec. 1920 - July 1921 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Cressey Colony Documents ”. Correspondence accompanying documents to and from S.F. where they were executed., 1920 and 1921 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Water Rights, Royalties and Up Keep ”., 1920-1921 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Agriculture ”. Predominantly intermanagement memos re: buying, selling and cultivating agricultural lands., 1920 and 1921 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Proposed Jordan Atwater Canal, Dallas Property”. C-H Co. discusses repairing a canal running through neighboring lands belonging to Barry Dallas. (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. Yamato Colony Documents ”. Correspondence accompanying documents to and from S.F. where they were executed., 1920 and 1921 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Merced River Tract ”. Sale of land., 1920 and 1921 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Merced Colonies #2 and #3 and J.R. Wilson Deal ”. Real Estate business correspondence., 1920 and 1921 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Dean Fields ”., 1920 and 1921 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co.-Canal System ”. Re: up keep of system and charges to people who use water., 1920 and 1921 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Miscellaneous Real Estate ”. Propositions to buy and sell land., 1920 and 1921 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Railroad Commission Correspondence ”. People took up certain complaints against C-H Co. with R.R. Comm. instead of going to court., 1920 and 1921 (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Sale of Agricultural Land ”., 1920 and 1921 (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Oil in Merced ”. Correspondence re: geological survey, oil leases and other oil related ventures on C-H Co. (Merced) land., 1921 (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Loan to Elmer Murchie ”. Murchie, the engineer for C-H Co., asks for $5,000 to build a house., July to Sept. 1921 (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Misc. Financial Data ”., 1911-1915 (Box 46, Folder 20)
- C-H Co. Livestock Tallies and Morse and Thane Correspondence (begin)
  - “C-H L. & W. Co. - Monthly Livestock Tallies, ”. Some missing., May 1915 to Sept. 1921 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - “Index to Morse and Thane Correspondence for ”. Files A-Z, indexed by name of correspondent. All incoming and outgoing letters recorded., 1917 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - “Thane and Morse Misc. Business Correspondence ”. Letters written to or by Morse or Thane, often times to each other, re: business (mostly mineral) deals and propositions. Reports on specific propositions and projects., Dec. 1917 - July 1918 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - “Thane and Morse Misc. Business Correspondence ”. Contents similar to 47-3., June - Nov. 1917 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - “Thane and Morse Misc. Business Correspondence ”. Contents similar to 47-3., Jan. - May 1917 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - “Thane and Morse - Correspondence re: Iron and Steel Projects ”. Irelan Mine, Seattle area., 12/26/16-10/25/19 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - “Thane and Morse - Coke and Pig Iron ”. Notations and data re: coke and pig iron receipts on west coast, much correspondence between Morse and George Armsby on the War Industries Board trying to arrange conferences with Replogle (also on War Industries Board) and the Capital Issues Comm., Dec. 1916 - Sept. 1918 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - “Thane and Morse - Steel, ”. Business correspondence between Thane, Morse and others., Aug. 1918 - Sept. 1919 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - “Thane and Morse - Letter from John R. Mitchell to S.F.B. Morse re: Iron Ore Leases ”. Mitchell was President of the Capital National Bank of St. Paul, Minn., 1/2/17 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - “Thane and Morse - Milbank Johnson M.D.- ”. Correspondence with Johnson in Los Angeles, who seems to have been a business partner., 1/17 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - “Thane and Morse - Arthur L. Pearse ”. Pearse, from N.Y.C., is in the steel business and is interested in C.H.C.C. coking coal. Correspondence with Thane and H.K. Devereaux, a P.I. Co. employee under Morse., Jan. - March 1917 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - “Thane and Morse - Frederick B. Hyder, ”. Correspondence and reports between Morse and Hyder, the mining engineer and geologist connected with B.L. Thane Exploration Dept., Jan. 1917 - Aug. 1918 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - “Thane and Morse - Horace K. Devereaux, ”. Devereaux was a mining engineer and in charge of P.I. Co. mineral investments in the northwest, working out of Seattle. Majority of correspondence Morse and Devereaux., July 1917- Jan. 1918 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - “Thane and Morse - Horace K. Devereaux, ”., Jan. - June 1917 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - “Thane and Morse - George Stimmel, ”. Reporting the receipt of correspondence or an office visit re: mineral business to Morse., Jan. - March 1917 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - “Thane and Morse - C. Coleock Jones, ”. Jones, a mining engineer from L.A., corresponds with Thane, Morse, Hyder, Bailey Willis and others involved with P.I. Co. mining, mostly about Vulcan mine., Jan. 1917 - Dec. 1919 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - “Thane and Morse - Mark L. Requa, Jan. 1917 and March 1918”. Correspondence between Requa, connected to P.I. Co., and Morse. Contains summaries, reports and other data re: steel, coal and coke. Bailey Willis's report on the establishment of a by-product coking plant to utilize Carbon Hill coal. (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - “Thane and Morse - Coke, Pig and Scrap Iron Brought into California 1913 - 1916”. Statistics forwarded by W.G. Barnwell, freight traffic manager of Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe R.R., (2/17/17). (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - “Thane and Morse - Henry P. Adams, San Francisco Chamber of Commerce, Industrial Dept. ”. Letter to A.J. Gunnell re: U.S. Govt. records of capacities of certain S.F. foundaries and plants., 3/14/17 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - “Thane and Morse - H.F. Alexander, ”. Alexander was President of the Pacific Steamship Co., Tacoma, Washington and a business partner in a Puget Sound Steel venture. Correspondence between Alexander and Morse., March 1917 - March 1919 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - “Thane and Morse - H. Koppers Co., Pittsburgh, Pa. ”. Correspondence with C.J. Ramsburg and T.W. Sperr Jr. re: estimates of Puget Sound plant of Pacific Coast Steel Co., March 1917 - June 1918 (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - “Thane and Morse - Jonathan L. Slater, ”. Re: iron ore deposits in British Columbia., April 1917 (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - “Thane and Morse - J.C. Cowdin, May 1917 - April 1918”. Cowdin is with Bond and Goodwin (bankers) in and then becomes Chief Signal Officer of the Army, Equipment Division in Washington, D.C. Correspondence predominantly between Morse and Cowdin re: proposed Pacific Coast Steel Co. (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - “Thane and Morse - Harold Cook, ”. Re: purchase of land for ore deposits., May 1917 and June 1919 (Box 48, Folder 19)
  - “Thane and Morse - Smelting Different Ores”. Letter from David Hancock, consulting engineer and analytical chemist from Birmingham, Ala., to R.H. Elliot giving technical information on smelting, 5/28/17. (Box 48, Folder 20)
  - “Thane and Morse - Bailey Willis, ”. Willis was a professor of geology and metallurgy at Stanford University. He made many reports and analyses on the ore of P.I. Co. mines. Correspondence between Willis and Morse., 6/9/17-10/15/18 (Box 48, Folder 21)
  - “Thane and Morse - Ralph Pierce and William Bayless, ”. Bayless was an employee of F.L. Thane Exploration Dept. and Pierce was an attorney in Seattle employed by Morse. Includes correspondence and copies of contracts., Dec. 1917 - Sept. 1918 (Box 48, Folder 22)
  - “Thane and Morse - Wellington Gregg, ”. Gregg was connected with the Crocker Nat'l. Bank, owned steel and coal land and was in business with Morse. Correspondence between Morse and Gregg., June 1917 - Aug. 1918 (Box 48, Folder 23)
  - “Thane and Morse - William H. Crocker, ”. Correspondence between Crocker and Morse. Morse forwards important letters and reports on progress of mining business., June 1917 - April 1919 (Box 48, Folder 24)
  - “Thane and Morse - Bernard M. Baruch, ”. Correspondence planning a meeting and memorandum of a meeting between Morse and Baruck, then Chairman of the War Industries Board, re: Pacific Coast Steel proposal., July 1917 and Sept. 1918 (Box 48, Folder 25)
- Thane and Morse Concluded
  - “Morse and Thane - Rittenhouse Deal, ”. Correspondence with Earl Pier, P.I. Co. attny., F.B. Hyder, and others re: signing contract with John Rittenhouse. Also letters from Herbert Fleishacker and Roy Bishop., Aug. 1917 - Jan. 1918 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - “Thane and Morse - J.E. Johnson, ”. Johnson, a consulting engineer and metallurgist from New York is employed to examine steel properties., Aug. 1917 - March 1918 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - “Thane and Morse - Hayden, Stone & Co., ”. Re: steel properties report., Aug. - Nov. 1917 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - “Thane and Morse - Gebson Manganese ”. telegram from O.P. Roger to Morse re: possible purchase of 1/3 interest in Gebson., 8/24/17 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - “Thane and Morse - Darling and Noble, ” Darling and Noble were barristers and solicitors in Vancouver, B.C., correspondence with Morse re: North Pacific Iron Mines Ltd. Mineral Claims. File includes bill of Canadian Parliament providing for a mineral survey of B.C. and a Certificate of Encumbrance from the Land Registry Office, Prince Rupert, B.C., Aug. - Nov. 1917 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - “Thane and Morse - A.B. Hammond, ”. Re: steel project. Also included in correspondence: Morse, Henry Scott, Chas. Greene, Vanderlyn Stowe., June - Aug. 1918 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - “Thane and Morse - Ray Lyman Wilbur, ”. Morse asks the Stanford University President to help in any way he can to establish Puget Sound Iron Works. Wilbur promises to try to help., Sept. 1917 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - “Thane and Morse - Col. E.M. House, ”. Morse asks House for help. House declines., Sept. 1917 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - “Thane and Morse - Robert Munro, ”. Munro in Seattle corresponds with Thane and Devereaux, who employed him, re: steel project., Sept. 1917 - July 1918 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - “Thane and Morse - P.H. Smith, ”. Correspondence between Smith, V.P. of Mendota Coal & Coke Co. in L.A., and Thane, who wants to purchase of Occidental property., Sept. - Oct. 1917 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - “Thane and Morse - Frederic K. Struve, ”. Struve, President of the Seattle Nat'l. Bank, corresponds with Thane and Morse re: steel project., Sept. 1917 - March 1919 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - “Thane and Morse - Samuel Trood, ”. Morse corresponds with Trood re: the Catter's steel process., Oct. 1917 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - “Thane and Morse - Charles Meyer, ”. Meyer is with Bond & Goodwin, bankers in N.Y.C., the major underwriters of the Pacific Coast Steel Project., Oct. - Nov. 1917 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - “Thane and Morse - Corporation Name, ”. Earl Pier, counsel, writes to all the Secretaries of States in which the Steel Co. would operate asking if Western Steel Co. would be acceptable. Rejected by Washington State because name already on records., Nov. 1917 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - “Thane and Morse - Herbert Fleishacker, ”. Morse and Thane report to and correspond with Fleishacker, one of the major business partners in the Steel Project and also Pres. of the Anglo & London, Paris Nat'l. Bank, S.F., Nov. 1917 - May 1919 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - “Thane and Morse - W.R. Jameson, ”. Realtor in Seattle corresponds with Morse re: Renton plant site as a possible place for steel plant., Oct. 1917 and Oct. 1918 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - “Thane and Morse - Letter of Introduction for Herbert Fleishacker ”. To Bond & Goodwin in N.Y.C., written by Morse., 11/9/17 (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - “Thane and Morse - Southern Pacific Co. Report of Steel Brought to West Coast ”. From Pittsburgh and Chicago., 10/12/17 (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - “Thane and Morse - L.L. Patrick, ”. Re: Vulcan Mine and Butte - Goldfield Reorganized Mining Co., Nov. 1917 - March 1919 (Box 49, Folder 19)
  - “Thane and Morse - American Internat'l. Corp. and Midvale Steel and Ordnance Co. ”., Dec. 1917 - Aug. 1919 (Box 49, Folder 20)
  - “Thane and Morse - Miscellaneous ”. Correspondence, maps, Letters of introduction for Morse, Rules and Regulation of the Capital Issues Comm., June 1917 - Aug. 1918 (Box 49, Folder 21)
  - “Thane and Morse - Denny Renton Clay & Coal Co. ”. Letter of introduction for Thane to D.M. Hyman in N.Y.C. and letter re: steel from E.J. Matthews., Dec. 1917 and Oct. 1918 (Box 49, Folder 22)
  - “Thane and Morse - A.J. Rhodes, ”. Rhodes was Pres. of Seattle Chamber of Commerce. Chamber supports in every way possible the establishing of a steel plant. Correspondence with Morse., Dec. 1917 (Box 49, Folder 23)
  - “Thane and Morse - Seattle Chamber of Commerce to Daniel Willard, ”. Letters to Willard, Chairman of War Industries Board, voicing support of Steel Plant., Dec. 1917 (Box 49, Folder 24)
  - “Thane and Morse - Telegram to B.B. Nieding ”. Nieding employed by Carbon Hill Coal Co. directed by Morse to meet train and cooperate with Bailey Willis., 1/22/18 (Box 49, Folder 25)
  - “Thane and Morse - Steel Data re: Carbon Hill Mine ”. Memoranda, reports re: C.H.C. Co. development costs and plan of procedure., 1917 (Box 49, Folder 26)
  - “Thane and Horse - Reports and Maps I”. Re: possible locations for steel plant. Some correspondence, dated 1917. (Box 49, Folder 27)
  - “Thane and Morse - Reports II”. Financial and feasibility reports on steel project proposal. Some correspondence. (Box 49, Folder 28)
  - “Contracts Paid Out - Alta Vista Tract”. Contracts for deeds to Alta Vista Land, in brown wood container, arranged according to deed number. Deeds #116-500. (Box 50)
  - “P.I. Co. Contracts - Alta Vista Tract”. Contract for deeds, #501-573. (Box 51)
- Crocker-Huffman Co. General File, 1917 - 1919.